[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
me
knowledge is power
[Music]
i want to start it off wearing a mask
too
yeah um i want yeah i want this to be
even if my audio is a little weird right
now i'll take it off but uh
i just i want i want the world to see
that yeah it's 20 21 but like we're
still here
yeah we're driving
well and things things are the same
yeah we're all still we're all still
plugging along we're all still like
taking the punches throwing some punches
like we're we're doing our thing we're
we're going through the path
um for sure well so tyler milliken
uh i'm really glad to have you here
today ladies and gentlemen listeners
welcome to the junkyard love podcast
uh this is my friend tyler milliken
tyler how the heck are you hi there
yeah uh thanks for having me jake um
jake of rhines
as your uh your zoom name here is um we
were actually
for listeners out there discussing how
kind of social decorum has
is questionable as of now and because of
you know i'll take this off you know we
started
we're at home it's okay we're
technically socially distant because
we're in different states
trust me it's fine but um
but no it's it's interesting to see
how you know things like saying your
full name
instead of just knowing you is jake you
know um
being able to to see that because the
moment we all had to convert
the moment that the world went to
digital for these type of
interactions we saw you know everyone's
full name and their email and all that
stuff
and it's interesting to see
what social decorum items we retain
you know you still say thank you to your
cashier when you're going through
the grocery store and and you know paper
plastic
you know that kind of thing still exists
in terms
of that and and i know when when amazon
or whoever drops off stuff at my door
and they ring the doorbell and they
rush away because they're busy i open
the door and yell thanks you know like
so the please and thank you is
definitely still there but
the handshaking's gone you know that
don't like the handshaking is gone
it's weird it's weird it's really weird
it was definitely a signal of like
it's kind of like when you if any of you
use uh
slack or like microsoft teams or
something like that
or even just your your iphone or android
um
when you start a new conversation with
somebody when you start a new
thread as we've all come to learn it the
physical
um momentum of that was generally the
handshake
is a hi nice to meet you jacob ryan
yeah i'm tyler milliken you know and
that kind of began the relationship
that's what
kicked it off that's that was the check
mark box and it's gone
yeah it's well okay so like just
physically touching another person the
chemical within our own body that's
released is serotonin
and so we're missing out on like a
chemical i mean it's basically i've
heard simon sinek describe it basically
that uh trying to trust your gut you
know you're doing this big business deal
uh you're talking with some ceo of a
company it's like cool
you got the thing you got the thing
here's the paperwork i signed it i
signed it
all right well it's great to be in
business with you and you put out your
hand
and that's like the and uh i think it
was simon syndic he speaks about kind of
like if your gut feeling at that moment
is like something feels feels wrong like
when you
go to shake their hand or or you extend
your hand and they're like oh i don't do
handshakes or whatever
like before covid think about how
strange that would be
but now it's something we have to it's
just something we do
it's just something that you almost
don't extend your hand now because
it will you know probably maybe perhaps
make the other person more uncomfortable
and it also now i've noticed because i
actually like a month and a half ago or
so
um i was my friend had a pop-up shop and
i went by
and i was meeting one of her friends and
i didn't even think about it i held up
my hand we shook hands
and it actually slowed the tempo like it
was weird we both kind of had a
knowingly
eye contact like oh oh oh okay we're
doing
okay yeah it was it was fine with us but
it also
it it like caused a step back in me
meeting a person
by actually shaking hands so whether
whether coverts around or not there's
already this thing
that has changed our interaction with
people
right it's uh it's um if anybody you
know out there listening or whatever
uh the iconic in the avengers movies
when we get to wakanda and you know
steve banner you know bows or whatever
he's like we don't do that here
right like yeah it's it's it's kind of
that's that's
the whole world now with the handshake
when you you extend your hand
and they're like we don't do that here
you know because like cove it's a thing
like we don't
do that anymore and i just wonder will
it come back
or is it is it done i hope it is
the elbow bump where we're at the elbow
what were they doing the toe touch kind
of thing where your shoes
you know we just do like a break a whole
we do a tick tock dance move when we
meet somebody
we just start flossing and facing each
other
i mean i i'm curious if it will come
back you know i i figured
i mean i know in places like um i'm
pretty sure in tokyo um
if you go to say a supermarket without a
mask on like even before kovet
it was just kind of a frowned upon thing
like you would it's just polite
it's just mannerisms it's just like or
if you're sick you wear a mask
i think we'll have all those sort of
things um but yeah i don't know man i i
hope we have the handshakes back
the elbow bump puts a it automatically
adds this goofy like
the world is crazy and everything sucks
right
like yeah it's not normal and it's not
well it's just not routine i mean i
don't know
i have never done i've never had to
write a uh
essay on when the handshake was created
right like
i have no idea of the history of the
handshake but i can say that
as long as we've been alive it's been a
business thing it's it's
been in cultural society it's been
a norm you know and it's it's
for the most part been expected you know
i i i don't
know that i've ever been able to go to
um a job site or a a business where
business is conducted
you know not not like a grocery store
but like you go in a bank and you sit
down you meet with somebody
trying to think back even um my partner
and i when we bought our house and got
our mortgage you know
almost two years ago we went in and the
the main lady at the branch the head of
the branch at that bank
shook our hands yeah before we sat down
you know it was just it was
it was the greeting it was a come in
please have a seat
and she hi i am you know and she shook
her hands
you know so it's so fundamental and so
just in our nature that i
i i think with you i i hope it doesn't
go away but i also think it won't
i don't think it will go away only
because we've paused it for what like
almost a year now almost you know
and there's vaccines rolling out
and there's countries that have
completely eradicated coving cases
and are doing fine and stuff like that
so i think we're just lagging behind and
seeing it but
it definitely will be one of those
things that that is the
slower recovery rate yeah right like
going to a restaurant going to a bar
having a convention those things will
come back prior to handshaking because
it's
it's not viewed as essential
realistically
yeah yeah i mean i think it kind of just
showcases the
the low underlying fear that we all kind
of have
walking around with us like kind of just
a little low level of anxiety where
you know we're all we're all like oh i
think we should probably do the elbow
thing or
i think we should we all just don't know
just
well it's it's weird too to see um
a demolition man right uh was it it's a
film i think it's
1993 or something like that it's got
um the main character god what is his
uh a adrian yeah
yeah yeah so he's uh he's the main
character and
um he
somehow they find a way to do
cryotechnology blah blah they basically
put him on freeze for 50 years and they
thought him out
and so he he comes out and he's like
what the hell the world changed and 50
years is enough time for the world to be
somewhat different for sure you know and
so
yeah and so the world's different for
him and
he does a high five
and they don't touch they don't
physically touch in this in this film
it's it's something that again because
of viruses and stuff like that like they
don't
it's not something they do and so the
the other person that he
you know holds up their hand and what
you're supposed to do is like this
and you go and then like this like that
that close and that's
it and so when he's like the guy is
shocked
just shook he's like
like somebody touched me like i
i don't know if he like thinks like he's
gonna die now or
it's just but whoever does that he's a b
character you know
this is one scene but uh that actor does
a really good job of exactly how we all
feel
right now when somebody wants a physical
interaction
and we're not used to it like
we we've adjusted to not have it and he
just yeah i mean
he looks at his hand more than he looks
at the other person because he's like
did you just
physically connect with me did that just
happen you know and
i don't know if he's thinking like do i
get this amputated like
go wash my hands like what do i do you
know it's very it was very telling for
sure
to laugh at you know a film from the 90s
and uh and still see that like nope
whenever
whenever physical contact becomes part
of the problem
it just gets mixed it just does yeah i
mean it's such a huge change from the
way that we've always done things i
think that
like i don't know i think in the end
regardless of what ends up happening you
know whatever
whenever we come out the other side of
this whatever that means it's always a
weird sentence in itself right
but uh i think what it's gonna probably
require
is just whatever we are doing we need to
do it with confidence
so like if for whatever reason the like
it's no physical touch handshakes don't
come back around and elbow touching is
all we do
like i sincerely hope that we make elbow
touching
fun eye contact like like
make it the best we can i think we need
to look at what do we get
out of something like a handshake what
do we get out of our um
like almost controlling our first
impressions of meeting someone
or them meeting us and trying to show up
as kind of our best self
like you know you want to try to make
eye contact when you shake someone's
hand you want to you want to be open you
want to be friendly
well and it's it they always explain it
too of um
you know like firm but not like like
when someone has a good handshake like
the good handshake right which was
usually like well they're not
limp wristed it's not wimpy it's like
they they intended to shake your hand
and it's
it's that intent that you can't with the
toe tap or the elbow
you can't convey you can't get the
uh the the perceived commitment
to what they're doing why they're doing
it why they're meeting you why
they're shaking your hand you know like
if if i show up on a job site and
somebody's like hi
i'm your head rigger like i don't have
the confidence that i would
if i show up and they're hello my name
is jacob ryan yes
and and and it's presented and it's it's
it's a good handshake and
you now have this unfortunate
because we've built this on society
right like we've created this
but you have either a a
instant confidence or an instance not
sure
about this individual due to that 10
second interaction wow yeah i mean we're
definitely
and you're not gonna get that with the
with the elbow
you know like
i don't know what we're gonna do because
we don't necessarily have to go back to
handshake to
to remap our brains on this perceived
confidence and or perceived
you know this perception um but we
definitely have to do something
we we have to have some
new formal greeting that
gives us this confidence you know yeah
it's going to be super interesting i
mean i i think that
like i said just whatever we do end up
going with like whatever our new social
norm thing is when we meet people
that because because we're going to look
at okay what does a handshake give us it
gives us confidence it gives us eye
contact it really opens this
this new level of dialogue where you can
meet each other on like a
starts the thread yeah it starts the
thread
so i i think that whatever we do it's
gonna have to be just done with
confidence um and i think uh i was
thinking about
um kind of like you're you're a pretty
confident person
i i feel like you've like i've worked
with you in quite a few
um different live event settings um and
but and i didn't know you before that
but you were manager was it was it
walgreens or
was walgreens right yeah so yeah i mean
even that from a young age
like i imagine your first time you know
you're you're in your teens or whatever
it was and you're going to meet whoever
the manager was or whoever's
interviewing you
like the confidence that you brought
into that i mean i'm sure it was
kind of just like naturally who you were
but if you had to kind of like look back
now and say like okay how did i
approach those conversations how was i
confident as as a leader even back then
um and how can we apply that maybe to
after the covet thing
right so for for a great example
in any job interview and for anybody out
there who you know is curious about job
reviews and stuff
i mentally go into job interviews
not needing the job for one like just
make it not a need for yourself you'll
you'll find a way i don't care if you
literally have
ten dollars in your bank account and you
actually do need the job you know
like no go to your friends and ask for
for help or something while you're
looking for a job but mentally tell
yourself
i don't need this they need me that's
why they're hiring
and not only that but mentally
you have the job no do your research
know what the job
is know what the expectations are know
what they
know the answers to the questions you're
going to ask anyway oh yeah
can you tell me a little bit more about
the job you already know what the damn
job is
it's working as a cashier it's ups
delivery it's it's running live events
it's
pushing buttons it's talking to people
on the phone i mean
you know it's receptionist like whatever
the job is do your homework
know what it is you're applying for so
that way you're not surprised
and you won't look surprised because
you're not and so you go in and you you
talk with the manager
and that's given me the uh most
confidence has just been able to go in
and
i already know what the job is i already
know how to do it
i don't need it do you want to hire me
essentially
it's what it comes down to you know like
like um
if you mentally prepare yourself such
that
you are in a position where you're not
you're not needing it you know um
then you realistically can can exude
that confidence by just
being there because at that point you
know i'm not saying you
you're gonna get every job you ever want
that way you know i could probably go
apply as the ceo as twitter or something
like that right now and i
damn sure will not get it yeah yeah jack
is not gonna let that fly right you know
but i also know that like i don't i
don't need it like i'm comfortable
and i'm okay with that and i'm fine
being comfortable and
it is what it is and so i could still go
and interview
um a small tangent here is
i actually remember plenty of times
even in this last you know year with
2020 and and covert being crazy and and
the gig economy
everybody knows the story by now so i
don't have to harp on the story but
um i have interviewed
phone interviewed zoom interviewed in
person interviewed for jobs
but i had no intention of even picking
up i just wanted to see if they would
offer me the job
i had a better job anyway i i was
comfortable but i was like
this is experience this is practice
yeah and i mean when you open yourself
up you never know like maybe they maybe
you talk to them and it's a job like
parts of the job they explain you're
like oh wow this actually sounds pretty
good for what's going on right now
right yeah right right you know um
the the actual the the current position
what i
um just got done with at 2 pm which
for the viewers out there it's currently
2 26 p.m
so um what i finished my my shift at 2
pm
and then hopped on this call with you
was a work from home
monitoring webcast and stuff like that
like today i dealt with the rbc which is
the republic bank
of canada so i don't know it doesn't
matter to me
i'm going to talk about they were
talking about um today's
conference was all about senior living
homes fun fact
right and how they have not seen
because of covet they've actually been
hurting those facilities have been
hurting
um in terms of
intake in terms of new people um i i can
digress on that all day long but the
point i was trying to make was um
i got emailed this link that said that
this company was hiring
back in august and i was like well i'm
already just sitting at home on my
computer
i have nothing else going on do i need
the money
no my bills are fine gigs have slowly
transitioned and i've been okay i've you
know been able to pay everything that i
need to pay
i i of 2020 i still did fine
right like i didn't i wasn't hurting and
but i was like
we'll see what it's about because the
the
email was very short and succinct you
know you have to do this blah blah
okay cool so i call them and the first
person i talk to
to do a initial interview to just her
job was to make sure you could speak
english
and had a phone uh and a good internet
connection that was her job she kind of
weeded out the people who
obviously were just not qualified
um she didn't really know much about the
actual position
and so okay cool whatever right well
sure
uh put me down for an interview with the
actual supervisor
three days from now i don't know if i
want to do it the pay is low and
whatever but but put me down might as
well
again i'm sitting at home i have nothing
else to do you know
and so three days later i get on the
phone with the supervisor
and he's like well here's actually what
you'd be doing
here's actually the job like not just
the job description but like the
the um the steps that you would be going
through
daily every hour to manage these these
webcasts
i was like oh that's super easy like i'm
used to having to do this
you know for like people on stage and
stage manage and graphics and live and
he's like no no you just
you call in you ask their name you make
sure you can hear them okay and then
when they're ready to go live you click
this one button
and you're like when do i hit the winner
bars
honestly like i'm over here i'm like so
wait you have
three people assigned to all these calls
and we all kind of cover each other
like which what like i'm used to having
three times this
work plus not three people yeah this is
so
backwards but again you know makes sense
why the pay is
um so this was an opportunity that
a colleague of ours actually emailed
myself and megan who's another colleague
of ours
uh emailed both of us this link because
at the
current time this colleague
uh was work from home with well not even
really work was just told to be at home
and still get paid uh with
apple apple corporation and uh darian
right he lives out in california
and their retail stores have been closed
and he was a retail
genius bar associate or whatever so
for the first few months he
just got paid to just not go to work
must be nice right i mean again for all
those watching you know
what the last nine months have been like
and
anybody in in jake and and
my industry we could call it but the gig
economy realistically anybody in in gig
life um has been hurting and it
really really really it it hurts it
the knife just gets turned in the wound
to hear that
huge corporations like apple were like
yeah just sit at home
here's your paycheck yeah we can just do
online sales
and then to twist the knife even more
was this particular individual and and
uh jake i know you mentioned editing if
i say something i don't mind saying this
to the world
um darian started complaining
when apple decided to make him work
i don't know and fedex him a a second
imac he owns one already so now he has
another imac
he was like i have to get my desk all
cleaned out and now i'm gonna have to do
online support and like this is annoying
i have to be training and it sucks and i
was like
oh it's so horrible to still be employed
yeah they offered your job
like well but no they didn't even offer
you a job like i get that this isn't the
job
that you applied for and signed up for
because you applied for and signed up
for a genius bar position in a retail
store in california and now
i'm sorry you're being paid these same
getting supplied the same equipment that
you had in the store to do your job so
another imac right just
now you have one at home with all the
same tools and everything else all the
access
you're getting a stipend for your
internet
so like they're already covering just in
case you happen to live at home and not
have internet you know they're paying
for it to make sure you can
and you're being asked to work for your
money
yeah i
you mean you can exchange work
for like money and then money for goods
and services and you're mad at that like
that's
that's what i don't know it was
i understand if they went from you have
to help people
understand and fix their phones and and
learn and and
you walk people through the stuff and
now because of covid the stores are
closed
so you actually have to physically make
the phone
you know like or um we need you to run
our board meeting with our ceos and
stuff like that like i'm not qualified
for that you know you're not paying me
for that kind of thing like no they
asked you to go from
like a handshake thing they asked you to
go from
meeting someone physically and helping
them
to digitally on the phone or
on chat helping people
that's it and from the comfort of your
own home
with equipment supplied and again it
comes all the way back to the whole
for four months the first four months
you were paid to just be home because
they thought everyone
everyone thought this will be gone soon
yeah you know
i don't care and i don't care if it was
a
you thought that because at the time the
and i can say this today the current
president
of the united states right so
so back then when we had the current
president of the united states number 45
was saying it'll go away and you buy
into that you want to believe that
that's
your own prerogative i don't care it's
it's thursday
january 21st 2021 and coat vid numbers
are still a thing so
clearly someone was wrong down the line
um
but whether you believe that or whether
you just were optimistic
whether you were j i was optimistic you
know i
i was in florida i still am and they
were like close the state for a month
it'll eradicate it will be good great
i had conferences and conventions and
stuff
in june and july and august that i was
looking forward to working
yeah i think we were i think we were
both at
i think when giggs first started getting
shut down it was it was middle of march
i think we were both
in waudeca was it we were up in bellevue
so i actually
yeah i actually have a um if we want to
cover that i've got about five minutes
worth of that
um we were both in seattle washington
and we did a show that
the morning session was saturday morning
that was our award session and then we
tore it all down
saturday afternoon we ship stuff back
and we had a good evening you know we
went out to eat and we did normal people
things saturday night uh sunday we all
flew out and
you know you you back to i think you
drove you drove back down
yeah yeah i drove yeah because you're
not far but
um the rest of us we flew out like 9 a.m
9 30 a.m flight whatever because again
you know seattle to orlando that's
almost as far as you can go without
counting alaska
kind of thing uh so it's a long flight
um
the next day well late that night but
realistically in effect at midnight
monday um the state the the city of
seattle
plus the state of washington both and
enacted a limit
and you could not you could no longer
have more than 50 people
for your gathering no matter what it was
and we had just
48 hours prior done a 2 000 person show
oh yeah i mean yeah we were in a room
with 2000 people
we did yeah we
we had to send home i don't know if you
remember i i had to send home on setup
day this is thursday so this is a few
days
i descend home our high school intern
student because
his school had one confirmed case one
yeah in a student it's so weird to think
i'm in the state of florida and i've got
i've got 15 000 new cases
a day we're sending home
somebody because they happen to go to
the same school
that had one case is that how much
that's what's going on right now it's
fifteen thousand new cases a day for
your state
it's average around yeah it's average
around fifteen it's crazy like i
haven't been following the numbers very
much but wow that just seems no i mean i
there's a there's you know a handful of
people at work who are going through it
i know quite a few people who have had
it by this point
um it's interesting so i remember at
that show at that same
show um basically i was sitting in
on some recordings and uh some of the
students were talking with with some of
the adults and
basically the students were like you
know they're they're trying to do what
they can you know they're
they're listening to the same news we
are they're they're getting the same
info we are we're trickling it down
obviously adults are trying to like
hey you know we're going to be okay but
we're going to do this you know you're
going to try to
to be that leader in in that role um but
i remember the
like one of the students basically kind
of
more or less saying i'm a little
confused i'm scared
are we sitting ducks like that that was
the question that he had are we sitting
ducks like he's like
basically asking hey are we gonna like
die this year or
and it's ah man it's so strange to think
of that was
you know nine ten months ago um but i'm
also kind of wondering
when we come out of this whatever that
looks like again
right i mean this whether we're
handshaking or we're elbow bumping or
we're
where we're off we're outdoor conference
only
we're outdoor concert only you know
we're sporting events but without
attendees
stadiums are being built but not really
stadiums they're just
soccer fields with cameras with cameras
you know who knows
so weird maybe this will push us over
into augmented reality world but i
wonder like what the
like like how could we show up as
adults you know like i mean when we're
in roles of leadership like when i when
when we're on site and like we're
wearing shirt and tie it's like
hey i'm in a leadership role like if a
student has something if he's coming up
to me
i have to stop you for just a second
because i don't wear a shirt and tie
i don't wear tie you know i
actually have laughs i refuse i refuse
um i i have laughed so much because the
uh
the production guide as of lately says
it's recommended
but not required anymore and i don't
know if it's because of me or what but
but no continue right when we are
when we are given and accept the role of
essentially a position of power or
whether or not you know i mean again
these are
we're working for them either way but
but we are
looked up to yeah period we are looked
up to
yeah i think that because like i i want
to like
as as an uh you know i'm almost 30 years
old like i want to
consider myself an adult who is going to
like 30 this year yeah it's not crazy
i like if a student
basically what i'm saying is like in
that situation i didn't have
any answers like he wasn't asking me i
just happened to be in the room um but i
was thinking like
if i had answers that would actually
comfort this kid who's like hey like
what's going on with this covet thing
like
are we okay i wonder in the future
like how can we because because kids are
smart man like in the
with technology and their access to
everything they don't want to be like i
wouldn't say
i wouldn't say they're smart i'm not i'm
not going to say they're dumb either but
but
i think that you're trying to touch up
there you go it's not saying they are
connected and like we can't just yes
because i don't want to i don't think
that adults should be feeding like
younger people
any sort of like santa claus story like
where it's like don't worry about it
like if you're good
santa will bring you gifts one day a
year like i want to be able to be
real and honest and open with our
younger generation like
but i'm just wondering how this is all
going to change you know i i always
think about
the the last four or five years i think
younger kids would have not really
cared about the presidential election
they wouldn't have cared about politics
but it's now kind of coming to the
forefront of all of us
with social media and stuff basically
like young kids
uh you know kids in high school even
middle school have phones and they're
connected to what
what's going on in the world and so
we're going to have to have some sort of
center truth or well so
so what you're what you're hinting at is
what unfortunately already occurs for
and has been occurring for for quite a
long time for our education system but
you're
you're you're saying censorship like
like i'm not saying
i'm not saying censorship in the the
broad bad way and stuff but but
basically
curated response or curated
flow of information is what you're
you're pushing towards and what you're
you're saying we should
we should have a consensus on and i
don't know that it's always
it's never always a bad thing right
nothing is always a bad thing okay but
but it is one of those like when the
education
system of a state or of a country or
whatever you know decides to
only push this flow of information and
educate like that's
what our youth know and with access like
they have now
to anything essentially i mean
the world's on the internet and if
they're on it then there you go you've
got access to
to whatever type of information you seek
you can't find
and i don't know that there is
i mean there are tons of the amazon
you know i don't want to say her name
because she'll light up but the little
doodad that's always in everybody's
houses
they make a kid's version of it that's
awesome
that's fantastic parents probably buy it
and eat it up that's amazing
who decides what goes on the kids
version who decides what
yeah like some 22 year old guy from
silicon valley who's just trying
somebody who has no kid
you know who reports to a board maybe i
don't like it because
i don't have stock in this i don't
rehearse one i don't have a kid so
i don't even know but the point being is
someone
it's if they someone decided it you know
um our biases are built into our
technology
the the iphone where you can turn on
parental controls
right like if you turn it on as a parent
you're moderating it as a parent you're
making that decision
but it
if not then you're right
i mean it's it's difficult it's very
difficult because
we do these events where we cater
towards
for for legal purposes minors
right like 90 of the people that we
are broadcasting to who are watching
are our hypodermic needle of what we
decide to prevent to them
and who we're interacting with and we
are talking with
are under 18. yeah and
and we have to decide how to
we center ourselves you know i mean we
we would never
you know this best of all songs with
explicit lyrics
oh she's gonna have to curate those
playlists and
you made that choice because someone
told you to make that choice
but it's not the parents of the kids
yeah so the parents of the kids decided
to send them to the organization to the
meeting and stuff like that right so
it's
it goes hand in hand but it's very very
i don't know that's why i don't have
kids um i don't i don't like
i haven't heard enough time making
decisions for my own dm self let alone
someone that i'm responsible for um
yeah it's it's it's very very
interesting how do you
go about letting the
18 and well under 18 generation
know that um again this is my opinion
with facts that you could google but uh
that covid is a thing
and it's not going away by a miracle
and cases are spiking and it's
transmitted
it's transmitted uh from from particles
from from your mouth and from breathing
and from the lungs it's you know it's
not on your groceries
it's not the under door handle right
like it's
it how do you how do you go about
deciding to
let them know the truth without letting
them know you know the whole truth
nothing but the truth only the truth
like we're supposed to speak on the
bible with their hand
like yeah you don't want to tell a 12
year old like hey to be honest like it's
a disaster out here nobody has an idea
what's going on and the politicians
they're all crazy
but like you want to tell him dr says
one thing and the president of the
united states tweets out something
completely awkward right i mean
i packed you a pdnj for lunch yeah dude
they're like yeah am i sitting duck mom
you're like i don't know go to school
like and i hope that they
what do you mean go to school i mean
that even broke right
yeah yeah go to zoom go to your room and
go zoom
go to your zoom room go to your zoom
room like go away
stop asking questions so for me to be
asked because i also don't know you know
and as a parent i think that that even
because again us
in positions of leadership positions of
power or whatever you know looked up to
feel like we should have a response and
a good one at that and
and we should believe in our own damn
response i can't imagine
being a parent with three kids let's
call it a high school an elementary and
a you know a middle or something like
that
and we've got three kids who all of a
sudden are like
why can't i go to school anymore and i
need laptops and
now i'm i'm parent and i'm daycare
and i am everything yeah and i still
have to work i still have you got to
feed him you got to keep him physically
healthy
you got to be making sure you're the one
teaching them the right things if
they're not learning it on their zoom
class like
i mean what's the right things though
that's that's yeah i mean i
just exactly what we started talking
about hats off the right to any parents
right now like
like sincerely like across the board
like
like i think parenting is going to be
like the bicep of parenting in the next
like over the course of the next couple
years is going to be just
fat giant biceps of every parent man
they're just going to be killing it in
the parent game because we
a lot of people have really been forced
into a whole different lifestyle with
this when it comes to teaching kids i
was thinking about
so um actually this morning i was
working on um
so for for some of the upcoming shows
i'm making a mix for aaron to play
um just a general walk and walk out yeah
yeah
yeah a lot of times i'll do we asked for
that so i appreciate it yeah yeah a lot
of times i'll do a spotify playlist and
it can
shuffle but this one will be a a
continuous mix and so i've been working
on that the last few days working out
this morning
and i was even noticing you know when it
comes to just right back to we were
talking about
um like who decides what is okay for
kids or who decides at what age they
listen whatever
even the explicit slash clean content
nowadays more and more so i assume they
have algorithms on places like spotify
who are um policing these things so if
it like it hears you know do alipa say
ass it's gonna okay now this one needs
an explicit content
no believe it or not it's actually under
the um from what i understand from
i graduated years ago so who knows it
was changed but
um it's the the fcc it's the same people
who decide
that that you can you can say [__] on
saturday night live because it airs at
11 30 p.m
but you can't say it on uh wheel of
fortune
because it's it airs at 6 p.m kind of
thing how do i do that with music
though when they submit the lyrics
well because so there will be ones that
will say clean like it'll say it's the
clean version or even on the the record
pools that i'm a part of
clean version and it's different than
the dirty version but it still says damn
it still says hell
because that's allowed on the
over-the-air
radio or if it's never a radio version
like if it's only an album version then
it that means that it doesn't have to be
regulated same way it's um
it's the reason that things like hbo
or netflix or hulu you know hulu
originals
netflix originals like they can have
full nudity and it's not a porn
because it's paid content no matter what
yeah that's true it was never
designed to ever be on
this comes back to the hypodermic needle
uh what i mean by that is
is you the hypodermic needle
is just an impression to say like you
can't it's gonna happen it's gonna go in
it is it is it's a one-way communication
and it's going in um
it's an old outdated honestly thing at
this point that i i kind of don't know
why i still use but maybe it's because i
was educated
but um but it's it's things so
things that are broadcast on publicly
available
free television are censored and
and scrutinized and stuff way more
than any cable tv show because you had
to pay to get it so like
you invited it in yeah right if it's
public i don't have to have i do have an
antenna because i'm cheap and i don't
have cable and i
do free tv but even if i didn't have an
antenna
the fcc is concerned
about all the content on those channels
because
they're just here not that my brain can
pick up
on those frequencies but they were
worried about it because
you do not have to there's no
i guess a good way of putting it is
there's no do you accept the terms and
conditions
for free tv yeah you just you can buy a
tv and have rabbit ears
and an antenna and you're done now now
you have access to that content
for free without accepting their terms
and conditions
no one's telling you you have to watch
it but it's there
and your kids could watch it or
something like that right so so that is
who decides
those things and why they're censored
but that explains why
even clean versions that you find
from an artist could potentially not be
as clean as we
used to come to know the name as clean
right like
a this goes all the way back to who the
hell decided that
it was a cuss word and why isn't hell
one oh because in the bible
right like i mean but who decided right
who
who made them bad it's connotation it's
always that kind of stuff you know so
um the garbage truck is driving by and
it's loud if you hear it i'm sorry
um i actually don't hear it at all oh
good well fun fact i do produce waste
and i have a garbage can i roll it out
um but no it's it comes down to
like who who gave connotation to make
that a cuss word
and then how does the artist who
produced the content with
a explicit in it um how do they
intend to get it to
their audience i guess i mean it's if i
sing a song that i made up in my head
and i sing it to a instrumental beat or
something
and i sing it in my shower and it's
literally nothing but what we classify
as cuts words like
that's technically not a problem or
explicit and i could
stream that on youtube to my followers
if i wanted to
you know um and it wouldn't be
classified as explicit either because
i never made it publicly available so
it's just me yeah
this podcast is a good example like like
we literally can say like [__] this
whatever and you can edit this out if
you need to but but we can say
anything we want to say and
because it's exclusive to people who
decided
to click on it yeah so it's not censored
i i'm pretty
like on on every single i mean i'm sure
there's a couple
episodes that i've uploaded that haven't
had cuss words but i pretty much assume
that my potty mouth is gonna slip out a
cuss word or two every episode at least
let alone my guess so i actually have a
thing on youtube and
on the sites that distribute it to like
spotify apple music all those
there's there's just a little check mark
check box mark like this contains
explicit content and i
like that because so for me
i i like being able to offer parents who
are driving with their like
age under eight child in the car like i
i want to let them know just like hey
let's do right now
and i want to pause you really fast to
say hey
you don't have any kids right so let's
let the listeners know your kids
do you have um siblings that have
children yeah
tons okay so you have you understand
the the the relationship that that
parents and children have
great okay i think they care about kids
a lot though actually i don't know if my
my sisters are the best example but i
know what you're saying oh
you're you're just letting me reel this
in okay now i have two things
right the first thing is you said
eight you said kids of eight or younger
in the back so you chose a number you
who doesn't have any kids
decided that kids of eight or younger
shouldn't be listening to your podcast
but nine enough was fine
okay it is the negative space you left
there and the second thing you said is
you think your siblings cuss too much to
their children so they're not a good
example therefore you
chose that that they're not a good
example and the negative space there
being
if you had children you wouldn't cuss as
much to yours
because they're not a good example you'd
follow a different example so
so you are now deciding in and of
yourself
as an artist that your podcast
this podcast should not be
um allowed
to be listened to by children eight or
younger
you chose that yeah like i'm the police
i'm the middle who
you're you are so who at the at
the spotify or the fcc or the tv or
netflix or whatever
decides that something that's rated
r right you can't go to a movie theater
and see something rated r unless you're
18 or older
but if someone 18 or older buys you a
ticket and you're
16 or 17 that's okay that's literally
their loophole
yeah uh-huh because i remember
going and seeing stupid films with
friends i mean that's what our
generation
did on friday nights after high school
you know we all piled in the one person
who had a damn car
and we rode down to the mall and we hung
out at the mall because the mall was a
cool place back in the day
for those youngsters who were like
what's the mall we order everything on
amazon
like um like no the mall was a place you
went and you spent
your allowance or if you had a job you
spent your money and
and yeah we would want to see a horror
film around
halloween because that's when they came
out and they were always rated r
because they had blood and guts and core
and all that stuff
and you'd have to sometimes have a
friend
like show their id like yeah i'm 19 and
uh and
he's 17 but like it's okay i'm his
chaparral
i was always the baby in my my group
yeah
you're with chaperone um right what do
you what do you think then like how do
we
what do you see like the future of
marking things as cuss words or do you
think even like
are we just going to mesh and young kids
are going to be
adult at an earlier age so to say and
like it'll just be kind of this like hey
try not to cuss but it's all around you
kids like is it gonna be like like where
do you see the future of
separating explicit and clean content in
our culture
so what i what i see is um i'll lean on
a colleague that you know her name is uh
christy howard
and um she she's got a little girl
and she educates her little girl
on language
essentially but but on on cuss words and
i think it comes down to the implied
meaning behind it
is where it comes down to and so we need
to instead of
shielding them from
a word because we decided it was a bad
word
you know um we need to just educate them
like it's a dictionary you know like
like we're teaching them language
we need to just say you know hey younger
generation
you can you can you can grab your cell
phone you can text your
friend and say what's up [__] and lol
and that's completely fine and
understood because you know
and you have this relationship and the
meaning behind it was just you're just
talking
you know versus imagine if your
six-year-old daughter texts her friend
says what's up [__]
i mean again like if the meaning and
understanding is there like it's funny
to say
because we've shielded for so many years
this this type of conversation and stuff
but
um but yeah like you don't if you teach
them the meaning behind the word
and the the emphasis on it and we show
them
that it can be used as
a as a comedic element
when referencing but also it can be used
as a
a negative insult you know as
essentially as an insult you know i mean
like if i if i tell somebody
you know like i i i can look at you
and we can be on show site and i can be
struggling and struggling and struggling
and struggling and
just absolutely struggling just just
struggle bus
9000 and um you come up
and in 2.3 seconds you're like oh
it's just control this for a computer
program or something right and like you
just
solve the problem that i've been bashing
my head against the damn keyboard
you're describing what you do on site by
the way like you you do this
you're you're the genie who just walks
up you're like oh it's just this
you are the example of that but point
being is
when that occurs even when i do it if
that individual who's been struggling
for 20 minutes
turns and goes [__] you like it's funny
it's okay
right right right you're not mad at me
you're actually happy that i solved your
problem you're more mad that like
your problem was a simple solution for
me and wasn't for you and i
you know i get to struggle i get the
frustration but that's that is a funny
way of saying it
um but then you can also you can like
you could be out of a club and you could
be like hmm
i want to [__] that way different it's
weird
not funny anymore not funny anymore
whatsoever
has a physical action associated with it
right
yeah you can also i mean
i've i've burned myself because i'm a
human
and you know it's scalding hot you're
like oh [__]
right like that's also a third version
like do i want to have sex with what i
burned
no am i laughing at what i burned no it
sucked
i burned myself you know like it's hot
so
you we have to we have to normal it's
it's a
whole trend right now if anybody's
watching this 20 years from now
scrub back in the timeline of history
and uh
around late 2020 early 2021 you'll start
to notice people going
let's normalize right and so we're
supposed to start normalizing things
well
maybe we should normalize every word in
the english
language it's and it's so
crazy for me to even say in the english
language overseas
we're u.s united states of america again
for those watching in
i don't know 2050 when this country
doesn't exist anymore it was a country
um brexit 2.0 right exactly
but um but over in
in the uk area [__]
is is okay
means vagina or [__] right
you know or or um
they they actually have more cool words
than
we do uh [__] [__] is also right you you
cocker
you know yeah but if you it's very like
yeah
if we say those those same words like i
mean two
maybe even all three of those words if
we say them they almost like stop the
flow of what's going on now
you can't say that i don't know if this
is like leftover christianity
um way of of just speaking or whatever
um you think it would really express it
then if it's religious
because we left and yes the united
states
is still religious but like not like the
catholic like
uk is hardcore about that we're very
like diverse
you know we try to be i know that
there's still hey those listening
in 50 years yeah yeah so okay
so i i think what i what i think about
so
as a dj and especially you know
doing working for student organizations
as i'm
also like i'm playing in clubs in bars
and at weddings like i like
i play weddings where i've played a
wedding where the bride
had me hand her a mic and she wrapped uh
palmdale by afroman word for word
like where it's just like cuss words
everything and it's even outside of cuss
words
i think in an ideal world situation what
we could be going towards
what would be nice as just someone who
plays the music
i think it would be cool to have i don't
know maybe
just a instead of explicit or not like
not hey this has a cuss word but
basically this is good for kids like
this is all right
all right for your kids under this under
this age or this is good for under 12 in
this year
or something but policing it exactly the
same
as everything that is on tv
if you turn on the little square that
pops up in the upper left right when the
program starts
well but so it shows up and it says like
13 plus
right or rated rated e for everyone
right or rated t for teen or video games
have this oh my god they still have this
today
you know where they have the little
square and it's it's literally policed
by someone making the decisions do you
think that's an outdated way to do it or
do you think we should revamp it you
think we should just let it do its thing
and let people be educated so
so i don't think that it's a i do think
it's outdated
in terms of you know it got created way
long ago
i don't think it's bad um
but i do want to say that
what those are those are those little
symbols and stuff on video games or dvds
if i don't know who
uses dvds anymore but you know whatever
on dvds on on
youtube channels on podcasts on netflix
where you literally are highlighting on
it and you're reading the one paragraph
description
it's got a rating netflix even does it
even though they don't have to
because they're you subscribed you paid
for it you're good you get but they do
it because they want their viewers to
use it as a guideline that is what it
was intended for and i think that's what
it needs to stay intended for i think
it's a good thing
it is exactly like going down the
grocery store aisle
and looking at the ingredients on
pick a thing you know does this have
high fructose corn syrup i don't i don't
want that for my kids
yeah you know does this is this organic
is this all natural like
if if you as a parent are cognizant and
policing
that element of what goes in their body
then you should be cognizant and
policing
what they're viewing and how they're
viewing and things like that and that's
on you as a parent that's why i don't
have kids i don't want kids and but i
do i use those ratings yes i use those
ratings it's
it's super cool to see that an animated
show by pixar says
you know tv 13 for for mature right
m for mature teens right that's that's a
fun one actually
the m for mature because that doesn't
put a number
which we all love to use because i don't
know the world went around the sun one
more time
and we happened to still be here so
we're like oh i'm a higher number
like who cares are you mature are you
mature enough to handle it
i enjoy things that just say what the
content is
and so it's again it's the ingredients
it's it's it's the stuff inside the film
does it does it have where they take a
chainsaw and cut somebody's head off
do you see it is there blood and gore is
there curse words
right explicit language you know as as
we've defined it
but but i i enjoy that is is there sex
have you talked to your kids about sex
yet and is there a sex scene in here do
you are you gonna have to
game of thrones you should probably not
let your children watch that if you
haven't explained like where babies come
from yet you know kind of concept
um but maybe there is maybe there's not
and that is for
you to decide as their supervisor
their parental element and i still think
the onus is on us as producers content
creators and stuff
to identify when that occurs so yes you
checking the box that says explicit is
helpful it should still be there i don't
think it should limit your content i
don't think that there should ever be
censorship for those type of things you
know i mean
if your kid can google pornhub or
xtube or whatever.com and watch porn for
free
then like they can also go on game of
thrones or watch netflix you know so
they can have their amazon do dad tell
them a real thing not be the kid version
you know so it's it's your choice
i think the rated m is um
basically like a coverall basis on that
and for mature
um i i believe that that
i kind of like that one again because it
doesn't put a number on it it just says
we we decided that you kind of just need
to grow up if you want to watch this
and here's the reasons why because m can
be because of violence and that's it
and can be because of tons of things you
know sex violence gore
murder uh language explicit content all
that stuff
i've i've laughed because i've seen
we've gotten too hard on the policing
thing
um so much so that i don't want
them policing if i had kids i think is
where i'm at because
i have gone on my tv my tv's this way by
the way it's what i'm looking at as i'm
referencing this but um
i have gone on my tv and i've just
laughed ridiculously
when i see amazon prime content and it's
rated
um you know rated r or
or m for mature or whatever and one of
the reasons listed is because of smoking
smoking is literally a reason to have to
rate your [__]
because people decided to smoke in that
episode and i'm like
what it wasn't
for anyone out there who hasn't heard me
already uh it is thursday january 21st
2021 yeah it was not but like what 30
years ago that that there were cigarette
ads
on the sides of buses and benches and
stuff and all that got banned
i mean we we remember i'm sure you do
the marlboro man
those commercials with him and the horse
and stuff like he was cool
yeah they they had there used to be
ads where it was a doctor like in a
white lab coat situation
like one in six doctors recommend mar
breads over ca
or over whatever like they those were
advertisements and so i think
retrospectively looking back i see
i don't know i mean i almost do see that
as
oh that's kind of wrong like that's
that's kind of like
that's you know they're gone yeah right
i mean so so it'll be interesting to
look back and see like what we're
looking at
explicit tags and in all this i mean i
think of someone who just goes let's say
they go to spotify and they hit today's
top hits and they hit shuffle and you
know they're they're driving down the
road like
even if you have the thing where it
plays no explicit content
you're going to hear like if they throw
a rapper on a duolippa song
and he's he mentions slang and rocks
uh has a has a strap
in his trunk like he did slang and rock
strap in my trunk there's no cuss words
in that
correct so like defined cuss words
yeah yeah so so there's another
implication
right like like so are those situations
where the parent like say there was a
kid in the car
for that example the parent says hey
that's that's the that rapper that's his
lifestyle that's what he's rapping about
blah blah blah
or or is there a sense that
it is almost wrong because when
we as young young people we idolize who
we like we idolize who like i mean when
i was young i idolized eminem like
i guess i didn't do things that eminem
does like i didn't
you know put a woman in the trunk and
drive down the road because i heard in
the song
but uh which could happen but i could
have been influenced to do it
yeah i don't know i just wonder because
i really do
see how um i don't know
like obviously through through working
um
like playing student organizations i'm
very like i'm a hawkeye with customers
now like if i'm if we're playing it over
the giant pa
and i hear like a cuss word that i
somehow didn't like i missed when i was
oh i know you transitioned instantly oh
my gosh i'm so i'm just my
my butt is just so puckered i'm so
nervous that i just lost my job for
letting one cuss word slip
but um i i don't know i
i i'm just i'm curious but what's
annoying was it
right that's what's about to say what's
annoying is it's not it's not just
jake has to make sure he doesn't play
cuss words he has to just listen to
everything
and not play cuss words like it's not
just that because
you have to interpret
and then judge personally the meaning
behind the song because there's been
songs that don't have cuss words but
they talk about
hooking up and taking a girl back and
doing all this stuff
and you're like i can't play that like
that's
i get that it's popular i cannot play
that
you know i i
let's go back to my place and do a line
we all know what that means
yeah they probably and then they'll say
coca-cola
and like add like the sound effect of
opening a can of pop
and then they'd be like well hey i'm
talking about the soda but
it's like we we have to treat the
listeners as if they're intelligent
because
you know to me they are like i want i
want the kids who are listening to
the popular music to like intelligently
understand what's going on like they're
not being lied to they don't need a
santa claus story but
there needs to be something i guess that
especially i want to take a note
especially the organizations we
serve are generally things like future
business leaders of america like don't
you want the future business leaders of
america to be smart
to be um trending you know to be woke
right like don't don't you want that out
of them don't you expect that
if they're in this organization we
aren't playing for the
viewers out there you know we're not
we're not doing this to
go to a high school and just put it in
their gym on a cd and call it a day and
they can
play and do a dance party whenever they
want for prom like no
this is a national conference for all of
the united states of america for
everyone in that organization
who qualified by competing against their
fellow students and happened
to be lucky enough to score high enough
to get to go to this conference these
people pushed and pushed and pushed
they know what the [__] is going on and
it sucks that
we feel like our hands are tied behind
our backs when it comes to playing what
they want to hear
[Music]
because you know that they go back to
the hotel room and they put on their
headphones like i am and they're playing
gucci game by the way
gucci gang guys you've got it
you know they're they're sitting here
and and all
you can walk down the halls of the
hallway and all you do is
we don't get to play that yeah yeah i
mean i and
i i get it though like it's it's very
frustrating it's very
it's i mean it's a difficult thing to do
i i weirdly enjoy it like
there's almost this like as much as
maybe
maybe i'll complain about it sideways or
something but like
as i'm sitting here spending hours and
hours not only
reading lyrics to songs as i'm listening
to them i actually have to ignore the
lyrics a lot of the times and make sure
right before the drop it doesn't say put
your [__] hands up or
just throw in a random sample of them
cussing or like if there's a little
vocal ad-lib in the background i have to
really like repeat it six times and
listen like wait is that saying
like like fight a [__]
you know what's really sad though about
what you're talking about is
because you just gave like a fourth
example of [__] i already gave three you
gave another one that's the fourth one
and what's so cool is it's actually not
even a bad one
like if i was working somewhere raiding
things and songs
put your [__] hands up for an edm
song where you want people to put their
[__] hands up like that's not
that is not a bad thing i actually have
a a random
um venn diagram that's actually really
funny i'll send it to you when i
uh when i get off the phone with you but
um
it has the different overlaps and one of
the things is literally
put your [__] hands up and it's
overlapped djs and guess what
priest
right you go to church and they're like
put your hands up and praise the lord
right you go to clubs and they're like
put your hands up and
and get down yeah and we can't we're so
censored because of
that whoever decided that that's a bad
word yeah
it's and that's what i'm saying as a
parent it should not be
it's it's not the word it's not the the
combination of letters
and and phonetics that make a sound that
make it bad
it's it's the context and the
connotation how it's used well look i
mean i think this time now more than
ever is gonna it's it has and it will
continue to
force us to look at the meaning of
things you know that's a lot of like
what's
what's going on like our political
differences and all of our arguments and
all the crazy news media
a lot of it is we we honestly like a lot
of us
really want the same thing it's just
like we're arguing different meanings
over each other's heads
we don't realize we kind of mean the
same thing we're so obsessed with like
no no the word itself like you said this
this is what democrat means
this is what liberal means uh it's
we're going to have to look at our
meanings of things and and reassess them
for sure oh yeah
touching on that i mean i really hope
that somebody happens to stumble upon
this because they have nothing else
better to do and they're
it's 20 55 and they want to listen to
jake and tyler talk
but um yeah i
i wholeheartedly agree with you we
cannot be black and white we can't be
black and white
on the word [__] being cuss word because
we have to look at how it's used in the
meaning behind it and we cannot be black
and white on
on any political uh controversy or
decision realistically i mean we're not
black and white
in the grocery store there's more than
one cracker
there's more than one juice there's more
than one there's there's pepsi and coke
and there's tons of variations right
somehow there's still dr pepper and
there's
you know special check k or rc cola or
whatever your when dixie or publix or
walmart brand is there's great value you
know and stuff
there's just so many different choices
that it's really sad to see
on the ballot and in the political
environment and in what feels like the
heart of america
too right right
and if you're not and if you're not
number one if you're not clearly number
two you're clearly yeah clearly you were
you were
you are a or you are b and there are no
other choices
that's a lot of the madness like that
that is one of the biggest things that
to me when i'm like as an observer when
i'm watching
like things that happen on social media
i'm just like what don't you guys
realize that you're just
arguing if you're not this then you're
that or if you're if you're not
with me you're the bad other it's like
there's millions of other options out
here
tons of other options and that's that's
what seems to
to fundamentally just suck with
um the choices we have and and the
people making the choices
and everything else is and honestly
what continuously stalls progress
because people in charge of making
progress
are trying to come to a conclusion come
to a unified decision come to
a middle ground and they're being met
with
way no because i don't have this i can't
do it or because i don't have that i
can't do it and it's
on both sides of the aisle i mean it
just
i don't i do not know a solution if i
knew one i'd be running for office and
i'd have it and we go
you know i do not know a damn solution
um i i cannot tell you if i think we
should go back to the drawing board on
on the united states of america
realistically or if maybe we can
dig ourselves out of the hole we we
painted ourselves in a corner
we decided that there would be two
parties really early on
and how those two parties would
be represented and and gain power and
stuff like that really early on
and no one's been willing to modify that
yeah i mean i i think my
very loose summarized opinion of what's
going on like kind of just with
kind of with humanity as a whole like
just where we're at but i mean
specifically like our country i just
think
what we have here and what we have built
here is completely beautiful
amazing like wonderful the fact that we
are the thing that came after monkeys
and we're not just like
throwing our own [__] around and like i
still do that you don't
oh i mean i do i if we were in person
right exactly to each other
but uh i i mean i think that
i think that we're just at a point where
we're our intelligence levels our
connectiveness levels um we are
changing at a very rapid pace and i
think we need to take a look at
hey what is the way that we are changing
in like like what's the direction we're
facing what's the direction we want to
be going in because
we're changing towards something
regardless so we need to kind of
put a little bit of maybe some some
bumpers using using like visualization
of like a bowling
right right um and i think that
guidance we need to add guidance to
our flow of the future because either
way it's coming
into it it's happening yeah and i i
think we're just
i mean we're at a time where i hope it
doesn't descend into madness before we
really get there but we do need some
sort of democracy 2.0 or new ways of
organizing ourselves yeah it's about say
i don't
i like your your bowling ball bumpers
analogy and i want to use that
and t on it unfortunately
what i was trying to get at with the the
current climate the two systems and
stuff and
and it looks it's we're hopeful um
again thursday january 21st 21 where
we're
forward momentum will not be this
however
in the previous
12 to 20 years but probably i mean i've
only been alive and paid attention
not that much longer so i don't know how
long this has gone on but
your bumpers situation has always been
there
we never get a gutter ball because we we
go forward
okay so the bumpers have always been up
however instead of
guiding it as almost a pie shape towards
the
the inevitable strike it appears and it
feels like what we've been guiding it is
a pendulum swing
it's been the ball is going left or the
ball is going right it's not going to go
in the gutter we got bumpers
right now we're good but it just seems
like whoever
gets control of the ball
you know or the presidency but whoever
gets control of kind of where we're
going
tends to just drive it i mean it's a
hard left or a hard right man
it does not feel it has not felt in the
last few years
like we're just nudging it a little bit
our way or a little bit that way i don't
even say our way or their way it's not
our way or their way it's forward no
matter what it's forward we all agree
there it's forward
but it feels like we're nudging it it
doesn't feel like i should say we're
nudging it it feels like we're knocking
it
to one side or the other side and and
that's kind of been
why our younger generation
is concerned with it it's been why you
and i are talking about it
it's been why the history books will
reflect it and stuff
is that it's you know it's
it's too volatile it's too much rocking
the boat that
it's getting people up in arms and it
comes what bothers me is i think like
you
it um it stems and comes down from the
whole
you're right if you're not a you have to
be b
yeah is it black or white thinking that
we keep getting stuck right
everything i mean even what we were
talking about with explicit it's like is
it clean or is it not clean is it a cuss
word or is it
not a cuss it's like exactly is it rated
r or is it rated mature
or is it right who decides we're gonna
have to look at our stamp
yeah yeah yeah like like who decides who
get who gives it the stamp
and then like we need to be able to say
is these people deciding to stamp it
this way
is this helping us any longer or is this
something that we need to take a look
at because i think as a general like we
got to stop sticking into this black and
white this red or blue this
us or them and we got to really look at
what the reality is right in front of us
right now not how has it always been
how was it before whatever like use
these things as examples to guide us
um you know amicably but we really do
need to
quit the black and white thinking and
realize what's really going on
however that looks you know colorful
that's how it looks it's colorful and
it's beautiful
that it is so diverse and so colorful
you know um everyone wants to say you
know america the melting pot the
it's like a soup it's got all kinds of
things and stuff like we need to show
that we need
we need to man up and we need to show
that we aren't
just democrats or republicans we are a
united nation
the united states of america and we're
all diverse and we all have different
rules
and what sucks is um people get mad
about this because it's it's
i mean hell a a high school
has more clubs and divisions than our
political system does you know like it's
insane
but the point being is there's still a
school principle
and there's still hard fast rules for
all of them that they all have
you know kind of kind of almost like a
check the box for accepted terms and
conditions like they've all come to
terms with and they've been okay with
and they've decided and agreed upon and
there's a revision and we every year we
look at it we can keep going and stuff
and so
i'm not saying we don't need i don't
want like to use the word overlord or
something like that you know we don't
want to say that we do need a governing
body we do need a set of rules we do
need to follow a set of rules
um but the thing the cool thing is like
at a high school they don't really have
to enforce the rules too much
compared to like police and the streets
and stuff right like they
because they all decided on the rules
and they all
got them they all wanted them you know
like if if you want to if i told you
that hi
i'm um mayor of portland oregon or i
don't know
head of state whatever something like
that and i was like you know what you
can't drive
from 2 a.m to 3 a.m
you just can't it's my decision i'm
allowed to do that
you elected me to be representative of
you
so it's kind of on you that you know you
made the decision
by electing me that now i made the
decision to enact that rule but like
you didn't agree to that you don't want
that
you know and um this
comes down to a small topic that well
it's not a small topic but it's a topic
that
um that is really annoying in our
current
way of doing things way of enacting in
congress in a way of doing laws
is they their bills that are proposed
and then they get voted on
and what sucks is
they're not they're not your grocery
store receipt where they're line item
and itemized right like you and i always
have to get a receipt that's itemized so
we can prove we didn't buy alcohol or
something like that on it they're not
that
what sucks with our bills and our reform
is there a it's a
uh we want to pass article build 1938
or whatever whatever the number is next
language and whatever
is inside of it is a yay or nay that's
your two choices back to the black and
white it either passes or it doesn't
right but if it passes everything that's
in it
goes so if it says we're gonna you know
what
we're gonna feed the homeless million
dollars right here
or billion or i don't care trillion pick
a number whatever it costs
to feed the homeless we're going to do
that oh but the exact same amount that
it cost to feed the homeless we're also
going to buy nuclear weapons with
is that cool cool i mean being homeless
sounds good right like we should do that
and that's the headline yeah
and buying nuclear weapons like that
helps our military maybe it's not so
bad so it goes yeah
and what sucks is when the vote goes
through
and it's super split but one side has
two more it passes or it fails
even if one side has two more for no's
and it fails you know and so
again that's that's the hindrance of
progress that's the our system is just
so sluggish and
stupid that we can't if we
if we can't agree to disagree and so we
just disagree
[__] all gets done nothing happens yeah
and we're stuck and it and i
wish i just continued to wish that they
would revise the way that they're
thinking
to you know when they're doing these
meetings
if you got down on a smaller level like
the
the board meeting of an hoa or something
like that you know where they're like
okay so we're gonna vote on approved
housing
paint colors right like it's
inconsequential no one really cares to
be honest but some people have a few
opinions
and they vote and ninety percent of the
time everybody's like sure whatever cool
and it goes okay cool beans the problem
arises when there's ten people on the
board and five want to say yes and five
want to say no
and that's what we have in our political
system right now is half want to say yes
and half want to say no
to everything yeah
and so if we can just get down to if we
could just get
get down to the smaller nitty-gritty in
the same hoa environment instead of
voting on the six approved housing
palettes or whatever
do you like red is red okay and then we
ask everybody and we get their votes
okay cool
only two people don't like red but eight
people do so it goes
what about yellow oh basically nobody
like jello except what
linda linda linda linda likes yellow she
wanted
but no uh we're not doing yellow nine
people said no so
yellow's out so instead of voting on
what i decided this bill is
we're going to vote on the the morsels
the smaller pieces of it you know
um when you go to a restaurant and you
order the meal
you get a salad you can say i don't want
tomatoes in it and they don't put
tomatoes in it when you when you do a
burger
and you say yeah i want the deluxe i
want everything no onions
no onions okay cool you get to choose
the everything good you want and nothing
bad you don't
but at our country level it's a
do you want combo number one or combo
number two
as is no no changes no exchanges no
swaps
have to choose it with the onions and
then get it with the onions and the
tomatoes
and you have to eat it you can't you
can't open the bun and physically pick
them off either nope you got it yeah
yeah we're just complicated that's how
our
our problem so i mean i think i i think
overall again it's just like we
do need to start thinking less black and
white and i would say we
as in like i think you and i don't don't
entirely think just in black and white
but i think you know
as a generation you and i are forced to
we just
uh two months ago went to a voting
location and had to choose an a or a b
yeah we're forced to
yeah we had to say yes or no on
different bills
there was there's literally a
proposition from my
just county location about a um
a like nature area pond
whatever whatever with a bunch of
turtles and stuff in it like wildlife
there was
wildlife somewhere i don't know the
exact location
and anyway this neighborhood was like we
want a second
entrance to a main road so we want to
like pave a road through this wildlife
and what we'll do is we'll relocate
the turtles turtles we'll relocate the
turtles to another
pond but if you read the entire article
they were only going to take up to up to
up
to 10 of the population of turtles and
relocate them oh
sneaky bastard if you actually read all
the stuff and so i was like [__] no you
don't need to do road like drive
drive around do you have a car i got the
turtles live
yeah let the trees be it's fine but that
was literally on my bill
and again it was a yes or no yeah there
was no like
well i would let you have your road i
could i would be fine with you could
have your cake and eat it too
if you moved all the turtles yeah and
built like a habitat for them
yeah because you're not saying like [__]
you you don't get a road it's like hey
no the the amount of turtles that you're
planning on bringing is the problem here
but you're not allowed to take that
onion as a substitute you know exactly
i was not allowed to i could not like
write in
a new bill and say this is kind of how i
would solve the problem
yeah and i agree to this as my vote so
my vote was
no you're not allowed to build your road
not that i have any qualms with that
neighborhood having a second entrance to
the road it's the way they were going to
go about it
right that's the problem yeah i mean
yeah that's a huge summarization of kind
of
everything that's going on we do need we
just need less
if you're not this than that i don't
know how it's going to happen it's not
like it's a magical overnight thing
thing but i think when we could all
bring into our own levels of awareness
and our own being
bring in like oh am i just being forced
to choose this or that
how do i feel about that am i just uh
extending as
to someone else as an option like hey
the blue pill or the red pill or
this or that or whatever i think we
could all upgrade our sense making when
it comes to that um
tyler we're getting up here in time i
know you have other meetings we are yeah
yeah and i appreciate that i um i
actually wanted to
follow up with one more thing and just
say because we've been harping on this
um
it's it's not always bad to have a do
you want salt or pepper
situation um baskin robbins
famously did not do more than 31 flavors
because
sometimes too much choice is too much
um netflix too many things to watch
cable tv
too many channels nothing ever good on
um
you know those kind of situations arise
when you do
have way too much so i i want everyone
to have a voice but imagine
just in my small example let's say that
that that community that wanted a new
road had a hundred houses
that's a hundred people's opinions on
what to do with the turtles and how to
do
everything and whatnot so so you know
the the summarization into bills
and the the coming together into a
unified response
is going to take time due to that fact
but
um you know it needs to happen
and i guess i'm just saying that there's
still
imagine back to the the the tv show
ratings or explicit content ratings or
whatever
like we already have i think we
discussed
smoking you know sex violence gore blood
all that stuff on there when do we end
up uploading the whole dictionary
being like well there's somebody who's a
redhead so like
caution if you don't like redheads you
know or or there's lgbtq content which
is a big thing you know like
how many tags do we have to assign and
when is
when is too much too much you know at
the grocery store paper or plastic
bring your reusable bags if you want
there's your three choices
yeah or no bags i guess there's four
just throw
if you just like carry your stuff out
but i mean or you're or you're saving
the environment i have to i
i have to be honest with you and um i am
a psychopath
um but i do enjoy shopping at aldi where
they
they charge for bags and said bags
aren't and they don't even bag your
stuff they just
you have to put a quarter in the cart to
get it um and then that means you return
your cart to get quarterback because
americans are cheap i'm it's so funny
that i see tons of
carts in the parking lot people are too
lazy to return i go i'm crazy about this
like i'm i'm someone who's like if you
don't put your cart back you're not a
good person like i'm
like it's a hard line i i don't know
dude put your damn car back here like
put your hand on cardboard
and stuff but anyway uh so so point
being is is i do go and i do shop at
aldi occasionally and
i have this um trunk organizer
which is just like this fold out thing
with a bunch of cubbies
essentially and so i don't do bags
because i
end up just throwing away and they're
going to landfill and so
i yeah i don't do bags i roll my
shopping cart out with all my random
stuff as a psychopath and then i throw
at my trunk organizer which is really
nice because it has handles on each side
and when i park i can just carry the
whole damn thing in it weighs like you
know a million pounds when it's full but
you can do one trip and you're in your
kitchen you're done yeah you being a
psychopath is
is saving the environment i very much
appreciate your psychopathness
good good um one last thing that i uh
yeah yeah go ahead but well well so i
wanted to uh just you know i want to
respect your time here i did want to
kind of like wrap things up i've been
enjoying this question lately and i feel
like you'd have a great answer to it
um what mr milliken what what do you
think
the world could use more of right now
like like what what does the world need
first off uh mr milliken is my father um
oh my
what can the world use more of um
let's see on thursday january 21st
2021 at 3 36 p.m
what the world could use more of is
non-apologetic patients
the world needs more responses that say
it's cool don't sweat it
um i got your back you know
and i'm saying that because i feel
like i'm not i i know i'm not alone but
i definitely feel like the
the world as a whole with you know like
all of 2020 and everything else is is
hurt it's hurt and struggling and is
needing needing
time so patience you know i i just got
you know we're trying to be respectful
of my time i am seven minutes late to my
meeting and i got a text message are we
meeting now
question you know and it's one of those
like i
don't feel rushed to answer that
because it's okay it'll be there even if
i was like sorry we can't meet today
we'll solve the problem tomorrow the
world's gonna keep going the sun's gonna
come up you know as far as we know i
mean [__]
we don't know is it the rapture we'll
see right exactly but uh but now what
the world could use more of
is just unapologetic patience i'm not
going to tell this
individual that i am eight minutes late
now and maybe it'd be another two or
something i'm not gonna say sorry for
being white
i'm gonna say hey here i am and he's
gonna be okay with that
you know because it's it's our time and
you know
you know i didn't meet my exact time but
i
still having our meeting the world's
still turning things are still happening
no one died yeah you know it's it's not
that big a deal
yeah i i suppose that's her saying after
saying
no one died uh for non-apologetic
patients if anyone listening to this
is perhaps like an emt or 911 operator
like please
with haste your job please respond to
that call
please respond don't call me later like
i'll let it go to voicemail like no i
don't know
yeah please don't do that yeah that's
not another black and white do you
imagine
calling 911 and getting a voicemail i i
like i've called 911 i think three times
in my life but i i just that's that
epiphany right there like
oh my god leave a message we'll try to
get back to you
let us know what's going on right please
leave your name and number and we'll
reach you back and our students giving
you
imagine listening imagine if your job
was the person to listen back to the 911
voicemail
where someone's like are you kidding me
you didn't answer you're 911. like
my friend's dying seriously yeah
seriously like like at what point do you
hang up and call back you know you call
again like
are they on do not disturb mode you
gotta call twice in a row or something
yeah you have to power call to get your
emergency to be at the top
maybe that's what we're moving towards
uh we might be but but anyway that that
should answer
it doesn't really answer too much but i
believe my main topic would be
um more on unapologetic patients
like just don't be sorry for things that
shouldn't be sorry for and be willing to
just breathe
excellent man i love it i love to end
there uh
that's that's a really great point tyler
i really appreciate your time man
um i appreciate i mean even just just
your friendship
as a co-worker your friendship through
that you've taught me a lot
um you're a great leader um you're
someone that i look up to
in forms of um just how confident you
are with meeting new people
uh with how you handle your workflow uh
it's just fantastic i i enjoy working
with you
and i'm really i'm really pumped that
you agreed to come on the podcast and
just kind of chat with me so
thank you so much yeah same thank you
for having me i really appreciate it and
i
um i i hope to anyone out there whether
they're listening to it tomorrow
or listening to it in 20 30 40 50 years
they honestly 50 years
i mean look back and be like man yeah
they went through some [__]
indeed so uh yeah
all right well thank you my friend
thanks for having me yeah definitely man
all right tyler have a good rest of your
day listeners drink some water
stretch and love yourself be a little
more patient with yourself
unapologetically patient hey we'll end
it with the cheers with the with the
waters
clink there we go all right see you
later buddy have a good one
hey folks i hope you enjoyed the episode
if you did please consider
sharing following subscribing leaving a
review sending to a friend whatever
if you did enjoy it and something stood
out from you maybe uh leave a comment or
send a little note on social media what
you liked about it or a quote that was
profound or
something we talked about that made you
change your perspective
anything you could do any interaction is
is helpful to me and
hopefully it's enjoyable to you so
thanks for listening we'll see you guys
next episode take care of yourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
you